'It's a comic?'
就是本漫画吗
No, it's a graphic novel.
不 是绘本小说
It's called Utopia Experiments.
叫做乌托邦实验
You had this. Where is it?
你们有卖这个 在哪儿
Just one of those conspiracy theories proved...
要是哪一种阴谋论被证实
-What about Utopia, then? -Tell him, Becky.
-那乌托邦呢 -你跟他说 Becky
Utopia Part Two, there must be something in it that they want.
乌托邦第二部 这里面一定有什么他们想要的东西
I also live with my mum.
我还和我妈住一起
Jesus Christ! You're going to make me cry now, Ian.
老天爷 你搞得我快哭了 Ian
My mission?
我的使命吗
You should persuade him to take it.
你应该劝他答应这事儿
What about the vaccine? Russian flu. I think we could reconsider.
疫苗的事你怎么想的 俄罗斯流感疫苗 我觉得我们可以再考虑一下
He signed.
他签了
He's fucking resigning, Michael.
他他妈的要辞职了 Michael
My mate's going to ask you a question.
我的同伴会问你个问题
Where is Jessica Hyde?
Jessica Hyde在哪儿
My name is Jessica Hyde.
我是Jessica Hyde
Come with me now or you'll all die.
跟我走 否则你们都得死
Who are you and what's going on?
你是谁 到底发生什么了
Ian, don't point that gun at me.
Ian 别把枪对着我
How... how do you know my name?
你 你怎么知道我名字的
Jessica Hyde?
Jessica Hyde
Wilson? They did this.
Wilson 他们干的
We all have to go now.
我们都得走了
We're not going anywhere until you tell us who you are,
我们哪都不去 除非你告诉我们 你是谁
how you know my name and what the fuck is going on.
你怎么知道我名字 他妈的到底出什么事了
Ian, you won't be able to shoot me.
Ian 你不会开枪的
Yeah? Don't imagine I won't, "Jess".
是吗 别以为我不敢 Jess
No, really, you won't be able to shoot me.
你真的不会开枪
You've got the safety catch on.
你的保险栓还上着
They don't generally have safety catches, except on telly.
他们基本上都没有保险栓 除了在电视上
Every second we stay here is a second they are getting closer
我们在这儿多待一秒 他们就越发逼近
and they'll kill us all. Please, come with me.
他们会把我们都杀了 和我走吧
What about my dad? He's going home.
那我爸呢 他会回家的
I've arranged for someone to pick up your dad from where he works.
我已经安排了人到你爸公司去接他
You don't know where he works.
你不知道他在哪儿上班
Davingdon's on Vesta Road.
Vesta路的Davingdon
They're picking him up now. I promise.
他们现在就去接他 我保证
I'm not sure about this.
我觉得不该跟她走
You two ready?
你们两个准备好了吗
Yeah, we're ready.
是的 我们准备好了
There's CCTV at both ends of your street. We'll go through the back.
你家路口都有闭路电视 我们从后面绕过去
Stay there.
待在这儿
What if someone's in?
万一有人在呢
Social uprest if prices continue to rise.
社会起义 如果价格持续攀升
The Shadow Home Secretary has suggested the Government's apparent
影子国务大臣暗示说
lack of planning could lead to outbreak of...
缺乏计划将会导致爆发
Is this your car?
这是你的车吗
You're so cute.
你可真天真可爱
Are you going to tell us what's going on? Who's after us?
你到底说不说 发生什么事了 谁在追我们
In the 1970s, the Soviets set up a germ warfare programme called
70年代 苏联开展了细菌项目叫做
Biopreparat. It was huge.
生物预备 很大的项目
They were weaponising anthrax, Ebola, smallpox, on a massive scale.
他们将炭疽 埃博拉热病毒 天花做成大规模武器
The West panicked and created an organisation to combat the threat.
西方世界开始恐慌 并建立了个组织来抗衡这一威胁
It was known as The Network.
称为 天网
It was based in no country, reported to no-one
不基于任何国家 不向任何人交待
and was utterly deniable.
并且被完全否认其存在
It did things democratic governments couldn't.
从而做一些民主国家无法完成的事情
They were insane, totally out of control.
他们疯了 完全失控了
What's that got to do with us?
这和我们有什么关系
Basically, that's who's after you.
基本上 就是他们想要你的命
You're fucking joking, right?
你他妈的在开玩笑吧
Right.
好
Do you know where that is yet?
你知道那是在哪儿吗
No.
没
I'll come later, anyway.
我过会儿就来好了
Gimmme the gun.
给我枪
We need clothes and money. Your accounts are useless now.
我们需要衣服和钱 你的银行账户已经用不了了
You're going to rob them?
你要去打劫吗
Let me make this very clear. Your lives as you knew them are over.
我在这里说清楚 你之前的生活已经到此为止了
What the next 48 hours are about is abandoning everything you knew
接下来的48小时 你们需要背弃所有之前的常识
or thought you could rely on and adjusting to the new reality.
来适应新的现实
If you can adjust you will live. If you can't you will die.
如果适应得了就可存活 适应不了就得死
Now we need to change the way you look.
现在得给你们换身装束
We need to get very far away and we need drugs for Wilson.
我们得逃之夭夭 还需要钱给Wilson买药
Give me the gun.
给我枪
Ian, hang on, can we talk about this?
Ian 等等 我们就不能讨论下吗
I mean, it's an armed robbery.
我是说 这可是持枪抢劫啊
It's adjust or die, Ian.
适者生存 Ian
I don't know what to think of her.
我不知道该怎么看待她
You could've fooled me.
说得像真的一样
You've gotta be fucking kidding me.
你别他妈开玩笑了
What, you just going to watch, are you?
什么 你就准备看着我换衣服吗
Here. Diamorphine.
拿着 二乙酰吗啡
What, heroin?
什么 海洛因
It's a painkiller. Do for now.
是止疼剂 暂时用着吧
You look good.
你看上去不错
Should wear that colour more often.
你应该多穿穿这颜色
You look shit. But in a good way.
你看上去糟透了 不过这也不坏
We need to get out of the city.
我们得离开这城市
We'll transfer to a van to keep Wilson out of sight,
得把车换成厢式货车 把Wilson藏起来
then burn this out.
然后把这些都烧掉
Do you have the manuscript, Ian?
你有手稿吗 Ian
Utopia Part Two.
乌托邦第二部
You need to tell me if you have it.
你得告诉我 到底有没有
We don't.
我们没有
Bejan never turned up.
Bejan没有出现
I haven't got Wilson's father.
我没有去接Wilson的爸爸
I need to do things to keep us alive.
我必须做些事来保全我们
Some of those things you wouldn't normally approve of.
一些你通常不会赞同的事情
This is insane.
真是疯了
Yesterday I was arrested for a sex crime, today I'm on the run
昨天我还因性犯罪被捕 今天我则是亡命之徒
from ex-government nutters who want to pull out my eyes.
前政府的疯子想要把我眼睛挖出来
I'm a fucking IT consultant.
我他妈只不过是个IT咨询
-Geoff? -Hmmm?
-Geoff -嗯
Have you seen this?
你看到这个了吗
Oh yes.
是啊
Those bastards have got real a bee in their bonnet about the bloody vaccine.
那些混蛋对那疫苗念念不忘
But they've named me.
可是居然提到我的名字了
Well, you did buy it, Michael.
呃 是你买的呀 Michael
In any case, there's nothing we can do about it. We're tied into the contract.
再说 我们也无能为力了 都签了合同
Well... we're not, actually.
呃 其实不是的
I've found a cancellation clause.
我找到了解约条件
It can be enacted if the department's total spend with
如果部门对供应方
the supplier is over 240 million.
的总花费超过2.4亿就可实行
It's to ensure diversity of supply.
这是为了保证供应的多样性
Yeah, but this is only 83 million, Michael, I mean...
是啊 可是这一共也就8千3百万 Michael 我说
No, but it's total spend. We get two other vaccines from Corvadt.
不 是总共花费 我们从Corvadt那儿还买了其他两种疫苗
Plus a wide range of antibiotics, cytotoxics, hypoglycaemics...
再加上各种抗生素 细胞毒素 低血糖药
I mean, this puts us well over 240 mil.
远远超过2.4亿
Have the contracts sent to me immediately. No-one to see them.
马上把合同发给我 别给其他任何人看
Look, whatever Corvadt are paying you,
听着 不管Corvadt给了你多少钱
we are not going to get away with it.
我们都难逃其咎
We can stop all this.
我们可以改正错误
We can stop it all now.
现在就可以做到
It's horrendous trying to conceive, isn't it?
想要个孩子 真是努力得要命
The medical nature of it all, the IVF, all that science.
药物治疗 试管婴儿 种种科技手段
A man needs warmth.
男人需要温柔乡
So I understand you fucking a prostitute, I do.
我理解你去操妓女
What I don't understand is you getting her pregnant.
但我不理解你怎么能让她怀上孩子
Do you think your wife will understand?
你觉得你妻子会理解吗
Get the contract straight over to me now.
把合同拿过来
It's for the best.
这是最好的结局了
Ian and I are going up ahead to...
Ian 和我要去
Great. Have fun.
好 玩得开心
Where are we going?
我们要去哪儿
I hack airline companies, look for people going on holiday,
我黑了航空公司网站 看谁去度假了
stay at their houses. They never know.
就住在他们家 没人会发现
This is connected to a trip wire in the drive.
这联接着车道上的触发线
Have everything by the back door, always be ready to leave
把东西都放在后门 随时准备在
within 60 seconds.
一分钟内逃离
What if you're in the bath?
如果你正在泡澡怎么办
No baths, no showers.
不许泡澡 不许冲凉
It's time to stop worrying about looking pretty, Becky.
这时候顾不得扮漂亮了 Becky
Are you trying to wind me up?
你是成心气我吗
There'd be no value to that that I can see.
我看不到这么做的意义(气你有什么意义)
You got a thing for tough women, is it?
你迷恋强悍的女人 是吧
Don't worry, Ian. I get it.
别担心啦 Ian 我理解
-Imagine her big, strong arms around you.-What?
-梦想着她那粗壮的手臂抱着你 -什么
You let us walk into this.
是你让我们惹上麻烦的
I mean, how much did you know?
我是说 你都知道多少
Because we had no idea. Look at Wilson's face.
我们可是一无所知 看看Wilson的脸都成什么样了
And that is not my fault!
那可不是我的错
Tell that to his dad.
和他爸爸说去
Because she doesn't have him, by the way.
而他爸爸 还没被她救出来
Tell us the truth. All of it, not bits, not pieces, all.
告诉我们真相 全部真相 如果你有所保留
Or I leave.
我就走人
Would you at least like to sit down first, Becky?
你想不想至少先坐下 Becky
No, Jessica. I fucking wouldn't.
不用了 Jessica 老娘不想
The Network was created by two men.
The Network由两个人共同创建
A geneticist called Philip Carvel, and someone called Mr Rabbit...
基因学家Philip Carvel和一个叫兔子先生的人
Mr Rabbit?
兔子先生
It's a codename, no-one knows the real identity.
这是他的代号 没人知道他真实身份
When the cold war began to wind down,
冷战渐渐退出历史舞台时
the various governments involved decided to back away.
各个相关政府打算退出
Only thing was, Mr Rabbit and Carvel had no intention of stopping.
谁料兔子先生和Carvel不打算停止
At some point, Carvel wanted out.
在某一时刻 Carvel也想退出
So they tortured him to keep him working
于是他们折磨他 逼他继续工作
and held his daughter hostage.
并把他女儿押为人质
Eventually, his mind snapped and he went mad.
终于 他精神崩溃发了疯
He was going be got rid of but somehow he was smuggled out,
他被来要被除掉 但不知怎么的被人偷偷救出
given a new name and hidden in a psychiatric hospital.
然后化名藏在一家精神病院里
The hospital was Shenley.
这家医院就是Shenley
And the new name was Mark Dane.
而他的化名就是Mark Dane
What, you...
什么 你...
you mean Carvel wrote Utopia?
你是说 Carvel写的Utopia
A therapist got him drawing.
一个治疗师让他画画
What he drew was...
而他画得
incredible.
如此精彩
So all the things in Utopia are real?
所以Utopia讲得事都是真的
What, like BSE, they created that?
就比如BSE 他们创造了那个吗
It's hard to say what's real and what's not.
很难说什么是真的 什么不是
But, yeah. BSE was theirs.
但是 BSE的确是他们的
How do you know all this?
你怎么会都知道
I'm Philip Carvel's daughter.
我是Philip Carvel的女儿
I was smuggled out with him when I was four.
我四岁时和他一起被人偷偷救出
I've been on the run ever since.
从那以后的一生都在逃命
Did you pricks give me heroin?
你们这群混蛋给我注射了海洛因吗
-We had to, for the pain. -Oh.
-我们别无选择 你需要止疼 -哦
Hope it wasn't Afghan.
希望不是来自阿富汗的货
Taliban have been altering it for years to make us infertile.
塔利班组织多年来改进配方 想使我们不孕不育
Everyone knows that.
路人皆知的阴谋
We need to find Utopia.
我们必须找到Utopia
We start with where it came from.
我们从它流出的源头找起
What? What about the others?
什么 那其他人怎么办
It's fine. I left a note.
没关系 我留了条
"Back soon, don't have a bath."
很快回来 别泡澡
Look, Wilson needs someone to...
听着 Wilson需要人照顾
That is not the reason!
这只是借口
Don't you see what she's doing? She's trying to divide us!
你看不出她在干嘛吗 她想拆散我们
-Becky, that makes no sense. -Then why take you and not me?
-Becky 这说法根本不成立 -那为什么选他不选我
Because you're not strong enough.
因为你不够强壮
I can't risk taking you.
带你走太冒险了
I know stuff. I know more than he does.
我知道内幕 我知道得比他多
What about Corvadt?
Corvadt的内幕
They're involved, they gave people disease.
他们参与其中 还散布疾病
What about Corvadt? They're involved, so what?
Corvadt又怎样 参与其中又怎样
They're a bit player.
他们只是小角色
You're not ready, Becky.
你还没准备好战斗 Becky
-Look, you just need time to... -Right, go on then.
-嘿 你只是需要时间... -好啦 去吧
Fuck off!
滚远点
What's that?
谁呀
It's nothing.
没什么
It's work.
工作上的事
Don't worry.
别担心
'I very scared.'
我很害怕
I know, I mean...
我知道 我是说...
They find out I pregnant, they angry.
他们发现我怀孕了 他们很生气
You just have to get me some time.
再多给我一些时间
Michael, I think I watched.
Michael 我想有人在监视我
Watched? By who?
监视你 谁
Don't know. I scared.
不知道 我好害怕
They come now. Michael, you help, yes?
他们来了 Michael 帮我 好吗
You good man, yes...?
你是好人 对吧
Michael Dugdale?
Michael Dugdale
My name's William Kaye, I'm a journalist,
我叫William Kaye 是记者
I want to talk about the flu vaccine.
我想和你谈谈那流感疫苗的事
-No, no, I'm sorry... -Listen to me! Your life is in danger.
-不 不 我很抱歉 -听着 你有生命危险
This isn't about a fucking story!
我不是为了登报调查
If I just wanted a story,
如果只是为了登报
I'd report the fact that you've got a Russian prostitute pregnant.
我完全可以报道你搞大了俄国妓女肚子的故事
There's my card.
这是我的名片
Things are going to get mad.
事情要开始失控了
You'll need me when they do.
失控以后你肯定需要我的帮助
Bejan got Utopia from the comic shop.
Bejan从漫画店搞到的Utopia
They got it from a dealer in Scotland...
漫画店从一个苏格兰买家手上买到
who is now dead.
那人也死了
And he got it from this guy, Jack Tate.
而他的上家叫Jack Tate
And who's Jack Tate?
Jack Tate是谁
The man who published Utopia.
Utopia的出版商
Mrs Tate?
Tate夫人
Yes.
正是
We need to speak to your husband.
我们需要和你丈夫谈谈
Right.
哦
My... husband's dead.
我 丈夫死了
Do you want to come in?
你们要进来吗
This was his study.
这是他的书房
Can you tell us where he died?
您能告诉我他去世的地方吗
The A22 under the Hailsham Bridge.
Hailsham桥下的A22公路上
He walked out in front of a lorry.
他走到一辆卡车前
I'm sorry. Do you miss him?
我很抱歉 你想念他吗
Of course I miss him.
我当然想念
Actually, I have something you might be interested in.
对了 我有些东西 你们可能会感兴趣
Yes, it's a... thing, I can't describe it, papers and drawings.
就是一个... 我很难描述 纸呀画呀的
That sounds like exactly the sort of thing we're looking for.
听起来正是我们要找的东西
We have to get out of here, now.
我们得马上离开
What? Why?
什么 为什么
You might want these papers...
你也许想看这些纸...
What the fuck have you done?!
你他妈的干了什么呀
She's with them.
她和他们一伙儿的
What? What are you talking about?
什么 你在说什么呀
Police turn up asking to see your dead husband and you don't ask why?
警察冒出来询问她的亡夫 换了你你不会奇怪吗（正常人都会问出了什么事）
Ah, shit.
哦 妈的
Glock 22.
格洛克22
She's CIA.
她是CIA的人
It means she knows next to fucking nothing.
意味着她几乎什么都他妈的不知道
That's how they work.
这个机构就是这样
They have people high up
位居高官的人
who get their drones to do their work for them.
手下有大量的无名卧底为其工作
You're going to answer my questions.
你要如实回答我的问题
And if I think you've told me even one lie...
如果我发现你有一点不老实
I'll put this wire in the water...
我就把这电线放到水里
plug this in,
插上插头
flip the switch.
扳开电源
Understand?
明白吗
Why are you here?
你为什么在这里
We got a tip-off.
有密报说
The man who lived here
住在这里的男人是通缉犯
has been wanted on terrorism charges for over 25 years.
是在逃25年以上的恐怖分子
We were too late, he'd killed already himself,
我们来的太晚了 他已经自杀了
so... so we took his wife in.
所以 所以我们拘留了他的妻子
Has the wife given you any information?
他妻子告诉你们什么了
I don't know.
我不知道
What did she say when you got here?
你们到这来的时候她怎么说
On the day he died he was talking crazy, he wasn't making sense,
自杀那天他一直在疯狂的胡言乱语
he said he'd been visited by a tramp...
他说有个流浪汉来找过他
"A tramp"?
有个流浪汉
"A tramp" or "THE tramp"?
是“有个流浪汉”还是“那个流浪汉”
I don't know, "the" maybe, or...?
我不知道 可能是“那个” 也可能是
Look, hang on...
听着 等下
I asked you a question.
我是问你
Was it "a tramp",
是“有个流浪汉”
or "the tramp"?
还是“那个流浪汉”
"The". It was "the", definitely "the".
“那个” 是“那个” 绝对是“那个”
She said "the".
她说是“那个”
- A select committee? - Yes.
-一个特别委员会 -是的
With powers to look into all aspects of the acquisition process.
有权力调查采购过程的方方面面
This is not going away, Geoff. They're announcing it tomorrow.
并不是大势已去了 Geoff 他们准备明天宣布
Do nothing. Keep quiet.
什么都别做 保持冷静
The morning will bring something new. It always does.
早晨就会有转机的 一向如此
Geoff, we can't do nothing!
Geoff 我们得做点什么
Well, it's sort of an order, actually.
好吧 这实际上是命令
Worry less.
别担心
Look, I know it's scary now.
听着 我知道现在情况很可怕
But tomorrow you'll be a hero, I promise.
但是明天你会成为英雄的 我保证
You didn't call in.
你没有过来
We were worried.
我们很担心
You're not agency. Who are you?
你不是警员 你是谁
No.
不
I'm not agency. I'm a specialist.
我不是警员 我是专家
What did you tell them?
你告诉他们什么了
What did I tell them?
我告诉他们什么了
They were going to fucking fry me, what do you think I told them? I told them everything I knew.
他们他妈的准备干掉我呢 你觉得我能告诉他们什么 我把我知道的都说了
Was it her?
是她么
Yeah.
是的
Yeah, it was her.
是的 是她
She was with a young black male, 25, 28.
她和一个年轻的黑人男子在一起 25 28岁那样子
Was a young man there?
有个年轻人么
Messed-up face, missing an eye?
面相残破 少了只眼睛
Er...
呃
no.
不
No, just them.
不 只有他们
Look, are you going to untie me?
嘿 能给我松绑么
Wow. That looks great.
喔 看上去很棒
It's like, um, pirate chic.
很像 嗯 海盗款式
How's your sight?
你视力怎么样
Er... I can see shapes and colours.
呃 看得见形状和颜色
Thanks for looking after me, Becky.
谢谢你照顾我 Becky
Where's my dad?
我爸爸在哪里
She lied.
她撒谎
She had to get us out, Wilson.
她得把我们赶出去 Wilson
I mean, he's probably fine.
我的意思是 他也许并没事
I need to find out.
我们得弄清楚
We can't.
我们不能这样做
They'll be monitoring our families, we'll put them in danger...
他们会监视我们的家人 我们会让家人陷入危险的
Look online, I'll show you how to disguise the search.
上网看看 我会告诉你如何掩饰我们的调查
I swear they won't know it came from here.
我发誓他们不会查到这里
Wilson, we can't.
Wilson 我们不能这样
I need to know.
我需要知道真相
Please.
求你了
His name's Milton.
他的名字叫Milton
Milton? Milton Wilson?
Milton Milton Wilson
What is it with your family and names?
这跟你和你家人和名字有什么关系
Right, you're sure they can't trace this?
没错你确定他们不会查到这个
Positive. He's a cricket nut, he logs in every day.
当然 他是个板球狂 每天都登陆
You'll see whether or not he's logged in.
你可以看到他是否登陆了
Is he there?
他在那里么
Hang on, I'm not in yet.
等下 我还没进去
Is he there?
他在么
Er... Yeah.
呃 是的
Yeah, yeah, he's there, he's fine.
是的 是的 他在 他没出事
Grant has the manuscript.
Grant那里有手稿
I heard them talking about it, they mentioned him.
我听他们谈论到过 他们提到了他
I weren't going to fucking tell her.
我他妈的才不会告诉她
Who are you, then?
那你是谁
I'm Alice.
我是Alice
What are you doing?
你在干什么
You're not from this school.
你不是这所学校的
Just fuck off before you get hurt!
滚一边去 不然我揍你
I'm not scared of you!
我才不怕你
What's that?
那是什么
Comic.
连环画
Well? Are you going to show me or are you going to be a twat all day?
是么 你是打算给我看看 还是继续像个姑娘家一样
Are you going to tell me your name, then, twat?
那你能不能告诉我你叫什么 姑娘
Grant.
Grant
Pleased to meet you, Grant.
很高兴见到你 Grant
Alice.
我叫Alice
Shit!
该死
Don't go.
别走
Same time tomorrow, twat.
明天这个时候见 姑娘
Are you sure this'll work?
你确定这样有用
Fanaticomix? Grant's addicted to it.
《连环画狂人》 Grant对这个很着迷
It's nerd heaven.
是蠢货的天堂
And you have to read the personals or you miss the good stuff.
你得读读个人资料 省得错过什么好东西了
I don't, but other people do.
我不会 但其他人会
But what if they're monitoring it?
可是如果他们在监视呢
Say to meet at the Embassy.
就说在大使馆见
Dane based the Embassy on the Taunton building
丹麦人把大使馆设在Hill Estate地产的
on the Kame Hill Estate.
Taunton大楼
Only a real twat would know that.
只有真正的蠢货才会知道
And me.
还有我
Never deny your inner twat, Wilson.
别否定你内心的小蠢货 Wilson
It's part of your charm.
这是你魅力的一部分
Oh.
哦
20...
and then six plus something equals 20...
然后6加上个什么等于20
Don't forget to brush.
别忘了刷牙
I won't.
不会的
Good night, Mummy.
晚安妈妈
Sleep tight, darling.
睡个好觉 亲爱的
Love you.
我爱你
What are you doing?
你在干什么
Can I sleep on your floor?
我能睡在你地板上么
I won't do nothing, I promise.
我什么都不会做的 我保证
Have you got that comic?
拿到那本连环画了么
This is so beautiful.
这真是太美了
Yeah. And that's part two.
是的 这是第二部分
No-one's ever seen that, just you and me.
没人看过 只有你和我
You're quite surprising, you know.
你真是令人惊讶 你知道的
You strike me more as a Spider-Man type.
我觉得你像是蜘蛛侠那一类型的
Oh, we should sleep.
哦 我们该睡觉了
If my mum sees a light, she'll come in.
要是妈妈看见灯光 她会进来的
Twat.
是姑娘啊
Thanks for letting me read Utopia.
谢谢你让我看《乌托邦》
Just to look after, like.
帮我看着 朋友
Keep it under your bed.
把它放在你的床下面
I-I-I'll come back...
我 我会回来的
for that.
回来拿它
Did they come back last night?
他们昨天晚上回来了么
Nope. Wankers.
没有 傻瓜
What we going to do?
我们该怎么办
I know what I'm going to do.
我知道我要做什么
I'm going to have a fucking bath.
去他妈的洗个澡
'We're getting more information
我们的突发新闻事件
'on our breaking news story -
设得兰群岛流感爆发
'the outbreak of flu in the Shetland Islands.
有了新的动态
'We can confirm two more people have now died
目前确定又有2人死亡
'bringing the death toll to 11.
死亡人数增至11人
'That's 11 now dead on the Shetland Island of Fetlar
现在设得兰群岛上死于疑似俄国流感
'from the suspected outbreak of Russian flu.'
的人数为11人
Shit!
操
18 dead, 33 infected.There's only 86 on the island.
死了18人 33人感染 岛上只剩86人了
Geoff's ordered a quarantine.No-one gets in or out.
Geoff下令隔离 所有人不得随意进出
Right.
嗯
If it's a new strain, it's got infection rates already of 58%.
如果这是种新型流感 感染率已经达到58%了
Michael, thank god you got the vaccine.
Michael 谢天谢地你拿到疫苗了
You're a fucking hero.
你他妈的是个英雄
You tell them my name?Did you tell them my fucking name?
你告诉他们我的名字了 你他妈的有没有告诉他们我的名字
No, no, I didn't say anything.
没 没有 我什么也没说
I think they're on to me.
我想他们是冲我来的
I think I'm being followed.I saw two men.
我被跟踪了 我看到了两个人
Jesus Christ!
天哪
Have you seen the news?
你看到新闻了吗
It's happening. I told you.
这会发生的 我告诉过你了
What do I do?
我要怎么做
I mean, people are dying!
人们在死去
We need a sample of the vaccine.
我们需要一例疫苗的样本
You can request one direct from Corvadt.
你可以直接向Corvadt申请
It's within your remit as advisor.There's a man in Sheffield.
这是你顾问的职权范围 谢菲尔德有个人
A scientist called Donaldson.Get it to him.
是个科学家叫Donaldson 把疫苗交给他
What about you?
你呢
Do exactly as I fucking say!
他妈的照我说的去做
The Tramp used to be a scientist with the Network. He got out.
流浪汉过去是个网络工程师 他出去了
Now he monitors their activities.
现在他监视他们的活动
He has to keep under the radar to stay alive.
为了活命 他必须低调行事
I reckon that's his office.
我估计那是他的办公室
A public phone?
一部公共电话
Here we go.
他来了
Him? But...
他 但是
He really is a tramp?
他真的是个流浪汉
Yeah, he's called 'The Tramp', Ian.
是 他被称为“流浪汉” Ian
Hello, Danny.
你好 Danny
Oh, shit! Oh!
哦 操 哦
Fucking hell!
操你妈的
You nearly broke my nose. You nearly broke my fucking nose!
你差点把我鼻子打破了 你他妈的差点打破了我的鼻子
Jessica, how lovely.
Jessica 你好呀
How did you know Utopia had a part two?
你怎么知道乌托邦有第二部
He's on our side, isn't he?
他是我们这边的 不是吗
There's no sides.
没什么哪一边之说
Just people who help you and people who don't.
只有帮你和不帮你的人
Now, now, Jess, you know a gentleman never reveals his...
Jess 你知道一个有身份的人是不会暴露他的
Don't make me ask you again, Danny.
不要让我问第二遍 Danny
Jack told me years ago.
Jack 多年前告诉我的
I went to see him now because I wanted part two.
现在我去见他因为我想要第二部
I knew Jack from the old days, you see.
我认识Jack是很久前的事了 你看
Why?
为什么
What's in it?
里面有什么
He never told me,
他没有告诉过我
and when your father died it didn't matter any more
而且当你父亲去世的时候 那就再没价值了
but now they have something.
但现在有了
Your father was working on a project called Janus before he died.
你父亲生前在推动一个叫Janus的项目
They've replicated his research.
他们已经复制了他的研究
They have it.They're going to test it.
既然完成了 他们打算检验一下
And what does Janus do?
Janus是做什么的
I swear I don't know.
我发誓我不知道
The last thing your father was working on
你父亲最后一项致力于的工作是
were viral delivery vectors that attack the human genome.
破坏人类基因组的病毒输送载体
And Tate? What did he say?
Tate呢 他怎么说
He said that this is the end.
他说要世界末日了
He said we are all finished.
我们都玩完了
And he took his own life.
然后他就自杀了
We need to work together, Jess,you and I...
我们应该合作 Jess 你和我
What I still don't get is what you were going to do with it.
我还不明白的一点是你对这有什么利用价值
I mean, what use would it be to a decrepit old sack of filth like you?
像你这样又老又脏会有什么用呢
What do you think your last breath will feel like, Danny?
你觉得你最后一口呼吸会是什么感觉 Danny
There's a woman. MI5.
有个女人 MI5的
They already have MI5.
他们已经有MI5了
Not this one. She's like us.Works in secret, trusts no-one.
不是这个 她和我们一样 在暗处工作 不相信任何人
She can help.
她会有帮助
Now, Jess, if you get me the manuscript I can get it to her.
Jess 如果你给我手稿 我可以拿给她
What's her name?
她叫什么名字
Please don't make me tell you that, Jessica.
不要这样 Jessica
Milner. Her name's Milner.
Milner 她的名字叫Milner
She's a good woman, Jessica.
她是个好女人 Jessica
Ian, we need a vehicle.You've seen me enough times.
Ian 我们需要辆车 你看我做过很多次了
It's time for you to do it.
这次该你了
Why didn't he give it to you?
他为什么不给你
Bit odd?
有点奇怪吧
I'm on your side, Jessica,you know that.
我是你这边的 Jessica 你知道的
I'm one of the...
我是其中一个
If we found him, they would.
我们找得到他 他们也可以
He gave up Milner's name like that.You saw what they did to Wilson.
他就这样把Milner供出来了 你看到他们怎么对Wilson的了
So you just killed him?
所以你就杀了他
- I pulled up the ladder.- What?
-我勒的  -什么
You fucking killed him!You took his life!
你他妈的杀了他 你夺走了他的生命
You just kill people if they're not convenient, is that it?
如果有人对你不利 你就要杀了他们 是吗
Why are you being so odd?
你为什么要这么古板
What the fuck are you doing?
你他妈的在做什么
They... They just came in.
他们 他们就这样闯进来
So you tied them up?
所以你就把他们绑起来
Children? You tied up children?
孩子 你还把孩子给绑了
We're making it look like a burglary!
我们要使它看起来像入室行窃
You did the right thing.
你做得对
We meet here tomorrow, 10pm.
我们明天晚上10点在这见
Keep Wilson out of sight.Stay on country roads, avoid CCTV.
不要让人看到Wilson 走小路 避开监控录像
You did exactly the right thing.
你做的很对
So, I-I-I want a sample of the vaccine.
我 我 我想要一例疫苗的样本
I-I-I'm sure you understand,with the events of last night.
通过昨晚的事 我 我想你们应该清楚
So, this is an R680 request...
所以 这是第R680号申请
Excellent, yes. You want a sample.
很好 嗯 你要一例样本
Yes, it's all filled. It's all in order. The paperwork is...
是的 都填了 都是按流程来的 文书工作是
What do you want it for?
你要拿来干什么
You are contractually obliged to supply a sample within 48 hours.
你们在合同上承诺会在48小时之内提供样本
Yes, of course. Something wrong?
是的 当然 有什么事吗
No, no, nothing's wrong.I just need... I want a sample.
不 不 没什么事 我只是需要 我想要例样本
I can do that.
我有权利这么要求
'Freelance journalist,William Kaye has been murdered
自由记者William Kaye在伦敦东部沃平的一座停车场
'in a car park in Wapping in East London,
被谋杀
'in what is being described by police as a gangland-style execution.
警方称是黑社会所为
'Mr Kaye was shot three times in the chest and once in the head.
Kaye先生胸部中了3枪 头部中了1枪
'Police have a suspect in custody,
警方拘留了一个嫌疑犯
'a Russian National named as Anya Lutchenko.'
一个俄国公民叫Anya Lutchenko
Anya?!
Anya
'Police have described her as a sex worker. The detective...'
警方称她是位妓女 侦探
How's your wife, Dugdale?
你的妻子怎样 Dugdale
Still trying to conceive, are you?
还想着怀孕呢吧
Still trying for a little baby?
还在为怀个小宝宝努力吗
Forget the vaccine, Mr Dugdale.You're not a spy.
别想疫苗了 Dugdale先生 你不是间谍
Becky, they'll be in the Taunton Building.
Becky 他们在陶顿建筑里
It's a huge water tower
那是座巨大的水塔
and, Becky, be careful.
还有 Becky 小心点
Grant's a city trader.He's bound to be a cock.
Grant是交易者 他一定是头目
Are you Becky?
你是Becky
Grant?
Grant
I thought you were a city trader?
我以为你是个交易者
Fuck me.
我靠
Don't worry. It's just Wilson.He's been hurt.
别担心 是Wilson 他受伤了
You better get in the back with him.
你还是和他呆一块比较好
Wilson Wilson?
Wilson Wilson
You look a mess, man.
你看起来很糟 老兄
Bloody hell, you sound about ten.
妈的 你声音听起来像10岁
Close. He's 11.
很接近 他11岁
What? Really?
什么 真的吗
You said you owned a Porsche and that your girlfriend was a supermodel.
你说你有一辆保时捷 女朋友是超模
Yeah, I've got ambitions.
是的 这是我的梦想
Stay here and be nice, both of you.
你们俩好好呆着
She got a boyfriend?
她有男朋友了吗
I'm just going to get some water for us from the shop, OK?
我去商店买点水
It's me. The manuscript exists.
是我 手稿是存在的
The boy.
男孩
The boy knows where it is.
男孩知道在哪
Where is Jessica Hyde?
Jessica Hyde在哪